<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programmer in Progress</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Programmer in Progress</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Uma introduação a JAX</title>
      <link>/post/intro_jax_pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/intro_jax_pt1/</guid>
      <description>JAX é uma nova biblioteca para Python da Google com foco em pesquisa de alta performance em Aprendizado de Máquina e seguindo o paradigma de programação funcional Mais especificamente JAX nos dá acesso a uma API compatível com numpy e scipy e transformações de função, as principais sendo grad, jit, vmap e pmap(que vai ter seu próprio post no futuro).
O Wrapper de Numpy: jax.numpy JAX nos dá acesso ao jax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Softbot Design with WANNS</title>
      <link>/post/softbot-design-with-wanns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/softbot-design-with-wanns/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m a Brazilian undergraduate student in Computer Science and I spent the past 3 months in the University of Tsukuba doing a research internship under Professor Claus Aranha. Here I will talk about my project during these past months to the best of my memory and in the end write down some lessons learned.
The research idea Softbot Design Soft robots (softbots) are robots built from highly compliant materials, similar to those found in living organisms1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate Practice in Competitive Programming</title>
      <link>/post/comp-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/comp-practice/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer, I&amp;rsquo;m far from a legend at competitive programming, I&amp;rsquo;m blue on codeforces and I will participate on IOI, I believe though that I know enough about CP and teaching that I can make some contribution
When you ask on forums about becoming red in codeforces, topcoder or atcode or how to get a gold medal in IOI, most people just say things like &amp;ldquo;practice, practice, practice&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;solve as many problems as you can&amp;rdquo;, but while this is better than nothing, it&amp;rsquo;s not the whole truth and is in fact a quite inefficient way to train.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Who am I I&amp;rsquo;m a curious person with diverse interests and a passion for computer science and math. Right now I&amp;rsquo;m an undergraduate student at the University of São Paulo.
My Resume
My github
What is this site It&amp;rsquo;s my personal website where I will blog about programming, host any web related projects and post some interesting resources
Some projects I&amp;rsquo;m part of Data University of São Paulo&amp;rsquo;s Data Science and Machine Learning Group</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/page/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/resources/</guid>
      <description>Math Resources Great Math Overflow and Stack Exchange Questions What specific algebraic properties are broken at each Cayley-Dickson stage beyond octonions?
Awesome Quora Answers A nice introduction to p-adics and their uses
Cool application of Elliptical Curves
Why Polinomials matter
Quick Roadmap to Algebraic Geometry
Beautiful Proof of Fermat&amp;rsquo;s Last Theorem for n = 3
Schrodinger for Mathematicians
Quick proof of Cantor&amp;rsquo;s Diagonal Argument
Why some &amp;lsquo;obvious&amp;rsquo; things need to be proved</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>